# **Lucas Machado**

São Paulo, Brazil +55 11 95452 9415 machadolucas@me.com http://machadolucas.me

### **PROFILE**

I am a Brazilian web and software development professional with experience in backend and front-end development.

I study Information Systems at University of São Paulo, the top university in Latin America, and I have an one year exchange period at University of Tampere, in Finland.

I also have a big interest and some skills in user interfaces, usability and game design.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Systems Analyst, UOL; São Paulo, Brazil.- December 2014 - Until nowadays. UOL is a Brazilian online service provider and internet service provider. It is the leader in Latin America and the homepage portal is the biggest in the Portuguese-speaking world. I am working in the development of PagSeguro, a complex payments system.

Software Developer, <u>Demola</u>; Tampere, Finland.- February 2014 - August 2014. Working in a team to create innovative solutions for real-world needs. Development of a risks data visualization tool (a turn based game) to the insurance field between February and May (Demola Spring). Development of an open source educational platform for the Finnish Ministry of Education between May and August (Demola Summer).

Software Developer, <u>E-Val Tecnologia</u>; São Paulo, Brazil. - June 2010 - August 2013. Requirements analysis for projects, development of functional and technical design documentation, application tests, and development in Java (frontend of banking systems; implementations of biometric services and authentication protocols, interfaces with cryptographic servers, with databases (DAOs), and CRUD models). Experience with implementation and testing of APIs, web services and user interfaces using scripts.

# **EDUCATION**

<u>University of Tampere</u>, Finland - Exchange student in Computer Science. *Academic year 2013-2014*.

<u>University of São Paulo</u>, Brazil - Bachelor degree in Information Systems. *Started in 2010. Expected conclusion in 2015* 

### SKILLS

Java technologies (Eclipse, JSP, Struts, JSF, Primefaces, Spring Boot, Spring Data, etc), SQL and noSQL (Oracle, PostgreSQL, MongoDB), web services (RESTful, SOAP, XML, JSON, APIs, etc), frontend development (HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, D3js, RaphaëlJs, SASS, LESS, Ajax). Python, Django.

Web accessibility, usability, human computer interaction, sketching of interfaces and image and video editing knowledge.

Project support tools: MS Office suite, Sharepoint, Jira and GitHub.

**Languages** - Native Brazilian Portuguese, fluent English and basic Finnish and Spanish.